# Riddhi Madhu

# PRODUCT MANAGER

### **PROFILE**

Hello! I am Riddhi Madhu.

Earnest product manager contributing to product roadmap development and refinement, research on the latest Web and Mobile technology trends, time to market product releases.

Strategic with proven history of SaaS product launches and success in new customer acquisition. Skilled in communicating with business stakeholders to understand the requirements and provide solutions inline with ongoing demands.

11 years of experience working on financial product development life cycles with industry success.

- +91 9820114984
- <u>madhuriddhi@gmail.com</u>
- in www.linkedin.com/in/ridhii-m/
- Mumbai, MH, India

#### **EDUCATION**

**Masters of Commerce** 

Mumbai University 2005 - 2007

**Bachelors of Commerce** 

Mumbai University 1995 - 1998

# PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

UI UX KNOWLEDGE

STRATEGIC THINKING

TIME MANAGEMENT

RESEARCH AND TREND ANALYSIS

PRIORITISATION SKILLS

WRITTEN AND VERBAL COMMUNICATION

PROBLEM SOLVING | AGILE

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### PRODUCT MANAGER

FEB 2021 - Present

#### AL MULLA EXCHANGE, (RADRAM QUALITY SERVICES)

Product Roadmap management (create, refine, maintain)

Conducting walkthroughs of product features to DEV and QA, tracking the development of the feature and demonstrate the feature to business team at pre-production stage.

Offered expertise to the designing team for better user experience, to the development team feature definition and workflows and to the quality team user stories and test scenarios

Tasked with product documentation, functional release notes publishing, monthly KPI updates sharing to management, quarterly updates on deliverables

#### **BUSINESS ANALYST**

SEP 2017 - 2021

Product Definition documentation, Diagramming flows and converting them to UI Designs.

Analysis on the existing business operations and providing ultimate solutions to streamline the operational processes.

Research on UI best practices and data modelling techniques

Involved in setting up the sprint cycles and development process for smooth production releases.

Set up the QA processes at initial stage of product development

# MANAGER, TECH PUBS / SENIOR BUSINESS ANALYST 2012 - Present DION GLOBAL SOLUTIONS (FORMERLY RELIGARE TECHNOVA)

AFMAdata system - Australia

Led the project starting from defining scope, setting up development milestones, tracking the development and delivering the product to Live.

Owned the Go-Live activity on-site to ensure smooth functioning of the system along with third-party integrated system.

Delivered product feature documentation and DR processes documentation to the client

dfferentia - FX OTC Derivative Pricing

Set up and owned the documentation of functional specs, user stories, test scenarios of dfferentia

Transitioned from technical writer to analyst by showing outstanding capabilities of gathering and eliciting requirements, writing product proposals and making presentations.

Learned pricing business logic for FX Options financial instruments

Managed content website including content, infographics and ensured regular updates for upcoming events and features

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

TWB FUNDAMENTAL CERTIFICATION PROGRAM (2009)

Institute: The Writers Block, Bangalore

INTERNAL AUDITOR (ISO 9001:2000)
CERTIFICATION (2008)

Institute: Unisource Worldwide Pvt. Ltd., Mumbai

CERTIFICATE IN ORACLE 81/D2K (2002)
Institute: Concourse Information Technology Ltd.,
Mumbai

HONORS DIPLOMA IN SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY (1998)

Institute: NIIT, Mumbai

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

DIAGRAMMING / WIRE FRAMING TOOLS Balsamic, Sketch, Gliffy, Draw.io

CONTENT MANAGEMENT SYSTEMS (CMS) WordPress, Magento, WooCommerce

DATA MODELLING TOOLS R, MS Excel

AUTHORING TOOLS

Confluence Wiki, MS Office Suite, Google Suite

# EXPERIENCE (CONT'D)

#### SENIOR TECHNICAL WRITER / TECHNICAL ANALYST 2000 - 2010

Started my career as Knowledge Associate working for Datamatics Technologies Ltd. The work involved was to convert PDF research report into SGML for online publishing.

Joined a Technical Writing organisation (Net Systems Informatics Pvt. Ltd.) and did some wonderful writing projects such as CBTs, ILTs and other learning materials.

Joined Unisource Worldwide Pvt. Ltd. as Senior Writer and Technical Analyst. Owned documentation for IT Infrastructure and application development. Got ISO certified and conducted internal audits for IT and HR business units.

Worked for Reliable Software Solutions Pvt. Ltd. for 3 months. Authoring product features, making presentations and handout materials for technical analysis software, Falcon.

#### **PROJECTS**

ekYC Process for New Customers Onboarding | eCommerece - FX Order and Delivery

KIOSK User Experience for Remittance | Product Website and Maintenance

How tos Writing project for StrangeHoot | KnowledgeBase Solutions for RighAnswers

Research Paper on Stock Market Analysis | Website Content Creation, Proposal Writing